

# **CONTACT**

/ A '	+44	740	724	705
	+/1/1	7/111	_/ <b>⊰</b> /I	7115
· ~		770	737	, 05

iuga.beatrice.dev@gmail.com

🙎 🛮 Birmingham, UK

in /in/ioana-beatrice-iuga

loana Beatrice luga

# SKILLS

C/C++	3 years
Classic AUTOSAR	3 years
CANoe Testing	3 years
EB Tresos ECU Development	3 years
• Git	3 years
Agile Development	3 years
• GHS Probe flashing & debugging	2 years
Polarion Test Management	1 year

## **EDUCATION**

## **West University of Timisoara**

BSc in Computer Science

Timisoara, 2016-2019

## **LANGUAGES**

English - Advanced

Romanian - Native

# **IOANA-BEATRICE IUGA**

Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer • Contractor • Freelancer

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a Senior AUTOSAR Developer / Contractor / Freelancer with **4+ years of experience**, only interested in remote work.

I use my expertise to help companies around the world to design and implement high-integrity software solutions.

**Drop me a message** if you think my expertise could help your organization!

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Continental Engineering Services UK** 

Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

Graphics Controller to CAN-Bus communication

Nov 2020 - Present

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was struggling with the development of a dashboard for a prototype electric vehicle because it lacked communication between two main components in the system.

- Increased from 0 to n CAN-signals being sent from the Graphics Controller to the CAN-Bus by designing a suitable communication method, using the Automotive Controller as an intermediate.
- Maintained the module for over 2+ years by updating the code base whenever a change occurred in the signal database file, and also by improving the communication method from simple INC to BIF communication.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, Google Unit Testing, GHS Probe flashing & debugging, Git, Jira, SCRUM

Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

**End-to-End Protection** 

Jul 2022 - Sep 2022

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was struggling with the development of a dashboard for a prototype electric vehicle, dealing with unprotected communication against faults between the Electronic Control Units of the vehicle.

Ensured 100% of the Application Layer's Software Components have access to E2E Protection when communicating with the CAN-Bus, by integrating a mechanism that offers protection against the effects of faults at runtime to the signals transmitted between the Automotive Controller and the CAN-Bus.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, GHS Probe flashing & debugging, Git, Jira, SCRUM

Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

Information Forwarding through Bridge Interface

Aug 2022 - Aug 2022

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was struggling with the development of a dashboard for a prototype electric vehicle due to the lack of information transmitted between two microcontrollers.

 Assured 180° communication flexibility between the two microcontrollers by developing an architecture to be the future foundation for transmitting information from the Automotive Controller's Dataset to the Graphics Controller through the Bridge Interface.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, GHS Probe flashing & debugging, Git, Jira, SCRUM

# Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

Date and Time signals to CAN-Bus

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was struggling with the development of a dashboard for a prototype electric vehicle because certain components in the system required to access information provided by the Real Time Clock for synchronization purposes.

- Eliminated the information shortage on the system's bus in under 1 sprint by forwarding the Real Time Clock information to the CAN Bus.
- Increased from 0 to 6 CAN-signals being sent from the Real Time Clock to the CAN-Bus by implementing an algorithm on the Automotive Controller's side that uses the Real Time Clock to provide Date and Time-related signals to the CAN-Bus.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, Google Unit Testing, GHS Probe flashing & debugging, Git, Jira, SCRUM

# Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

Application Layer Module Removal

Feb 2022 - Feb 2022

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was struggling with the development of a dashboard for a prototype electric vehicle, dealing with duplicate modules that were unnecessarily consuming resources.

 Reduced and optimized the code base by 10% by safely eliminating 2 obsolete modules.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, GHS Probe flashing & debugging, Git, Jira, SCRUM

# Senior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

Complex Device Driver optimization

Jul 2021 - Jul 2021

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was struggling with the development of a dashboard for a prototype electric vehicle, having trouble optimizing the mechanism for transmitting warning telltales to the driver's dashboard.

Reduced complexity of the communication approach by 5% between 2
modules based under the Runtime Environment Layer by correcting the
Complex Device Driver type of connection with the Bridge Interface Module.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, GHS Probe flashing & debugging, Git, Jira, SCRUM

## Senior C++ Developer

**Graphics Controller HMI** 

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was providing engineering services to an English luxury sports car manufacturer for the development of a dashboard for their new SUV car. Being in an advanced stage of the project, the client was dealing with unpredicted bugs in their Dashboard Human-Machine Interface.

 Closed 70% of the bug tickes from that period related to the Car Dashboard HMI, by working closely with the testing team and the other developers.

Skills: C++, CANoe testing, UI Programming & Testing, Git, Jira, SCRUM

## **Continental Automotive Romania**

Junior C/C++ AUTOSAR Developer

Classic AUTOSAR Internship

Jul 2018 - Sep 2019

The client, a leading provider of automotive software solutions, was developing a Driver Monitoring System on Chip, struggling to finish the implementation by the end of the deadline.

• Successfully closed 100% of the remaining topics, by supporting the team with the design implementation, and testing of the features.

Skills: Classic AUTOSAR, C/C++, EB Tresos ECU Development, CANoe testing, Unit Testing, Git, Jira, SCRUM